all right welcome to the inaugural
solution raising where we are going to
come up with a education solution within
an hour so what that looks like in is to
spend 10 minutes talking about the
problem what is currently happening in
education what do we see of us as the
issues what is working what isn't and
what is happening in this space without
necessarily explaining that something
what are the projects you know that are
going on in coaching that other people
could go and explore outside of this
then spend 10 to 15 minutes talking
about a potential future an omni win
ante rival risk proto pian solution
however far in the future you need that
to be for it to be plausible just to get
our juices flowing of like this is what
could happen if humanity work together
and and then spending half an hour
discussing something that we could
actually do right now if we had 10,000
people at $100,000 something that
doesn't require coercion or force or
government involvement just those 10,000
people creating a solution for
themselves and yeah so that's what and
then the other thing I wanted to say is
that let's have fun because we're trying
to come up with a solution to education
an hour that's a little ridiculous let's
just know that and that it's a very
short time period for each of these
topics not everyone's gonna get to say
what they want it's more about the
conversation itself emerging allowing it
to to happen what is what is gonna
happen during this hour that would never
happen as individuals coming up with a
solution and so if anyone would like to
start sharing for 30 seconds a minute
two minutes what they think education
currently is I don't mind going I've
brought a fair bit to this conversation
anyway I mean doesn't mean I'm not happy
to let things emerge right but I have
already brought a fair bit to this I
assume
to me it seems pretty straightforward
that the education system the model for
the education system we currently have
is simply out-of-date right I mean it
may have been a good thing 150 years ago
when you were training factory workers
but you know given the rapidly changing
circle
senses an environment in which we can
expect to be living for the future you
know training content and then the
ability to regurgitate content is simply
not fit for purpose and so it seems to
me that's pretty much what education is
anything exploratory the arts at the
emphasized because you can't easily
assess and measure outcomes in these
types of things the willingness to
experiment is all but vanished from
schools there's there's a there's an
atmosphere of fear particularly fear of
failure but fear in general you know of
what you know what if I do something
wrong what if I get something wrong what
if I make a mistake you know this kind
of thing pervades the entire fabric of
education I mean that's my experience I
was a teacher so I have some I have some
personal hands-on feet on the ground
kind of experience in this and so it
seems to me that essentially the entire
thing needs to be thrown out and
something entirely new built I I say
from the bottom up I mean Jubilee and I
actually had discussion along these
lines not very long ago and I know I'm I
know I'm taking up a lot of time so I'll
just say this very quickly and then I'm
done that you know the the purpose of
this conversation is to come up with an
idea something which could be you know
work towards right now I I kind of
strongly have the feeling that to have a
clear idea of where you want to go is
actually a mistake at this stage and
that really the the more appropriate
question to ask is what kind of
circumstances what sort of starting
conditions are necessary for a fit for
purpose flourishing education system to
emerge from in the same way that we're
having this conversation right we're not
starting with a particular goal in mind
you know in the same way we have you
know we have a set of aspirations maybe
but not like a particular picture
framework of exactly how the thing is
going to look and so I will stop there
sorry if I run over
anyone else want to add to our current
education sure just one note it might
actually make sense to swap the last two
spots on the agenda so it goes we cover
what we're ordering now sort of what we
could do like our next steps and then
the last that is as we sort of built up
towards it from the what can we do now
conversation there's that final like
what does it look like if it's perfect
quote unquote yeah I'm doing it this way
first visit agrees in but if it turns
out it doesn't work this way then we
could absolutely like that's the
chronological order right of where we
are to the step to be it's like getting
our juices flowing so that we can think
of the current solution what is a little
thing right oh I can see II either
working just be floating different from
actual input on education I
I mean agree it's sort of a mostly
broken topic Jubilee I'm not sure what
you found like going to our high school
was like but I actually credit that with
doing a lot of good things but it was
also really weird high school where they
like to be teachers went by first names
which is uncommon and also seems like it
should be normal
it's a small thing but I think it helped
and then also students that like
actually showed an aptitude in something
like for me it was computers for another
guy his dad owned like a little drywall
company and so he kind of got to skip a
lot of his classes and just go and shop
class and just sort of own that space
and the people who were into computers
we kind of got to ignore a lot other I
got excused from classes to go and help
teachers with computers I gotta execute
some tests to go and like fix problems
and so it seemed like if it seemed like
you knew where you were going they
de-emphasize everything else and off to
the races
and I spent my last two years in high
school mostly just doing you work for a
school which I found quite useful and
that's all yeah I I just want to add to
that I still from Eric saying that
kind of stressful days I still when I
have stress dreams they are about
finding my classes in high school I
don't know if that's part of just being
an overly sensitive teenager or if it's
just that scary of a time but definitely
seems to be more stressful than it
should be and and yeah you know several
hundred years ago it was possible that a
human could through a lifetime learn a
majority of human knowledge at that time
but now we have more content appearing
in a day than a human could learn in a
lifetime so yeah the you know memorizing
and regurgitating faxes that's no longer
sufficient
I think our education systems throughout
history have done a great thing as far
as bringing the human race to where it's
at and now it's time for the next level
I think the state of education right now
the difficulty with it is that we still
live in this stage where we like what
Eric said where we're treating students
like they're still about to work in a
factory the issue is we are under
estimating the amount of complexity that
has always been part of how much ways to
there can be to learn and how many
things there are to learn and so now
that we have access to communicating on
way higher bandwidth we start realizing
oh my god
not only is education ambiguous but we
need to find a way to keep education
ambiguous so we don't leave anything out
but at the same time we need to create a
strategy to go from the factory worker
mentality to a more stable coherent like
second wave of Education and I think
that's where we need to start and we
haven't even gotten there yet
you
I think you guys laid out a lot of what
is wrong with the education system so
I'm gonna touch on things that I think
are working in this space I mentioned
before we went live to Nick that like
the Khan Academy and MOOCs online I
don't remember what MOOC stands for no
you don't will no massive online
classroom massively open online
classroom look and having technology
available having basically every piece
of human knowledge available on the
internet right now the issues to me is
that it's not organized and you can't
access it in that way and you can't
learn the complexity that ins that is
there and access it in a way that you
don't need to memorize it and can just
just access it I also in this space my
kids school last year just closed and
now she's in a regular public school but
she was in a democratic school and
seeing the difference between calling
your teacher by the first name having
your teacher as a friend that you feel
absolutely comfortable inviting over for
dinner and comes to your house to
interview you when needed and does these
things that are just not done in the
regular public school system and now the
difference it is like my kid didn't need
to know how to read when she was in that
it would have emerged and it's right
time and now it's like she does need to
know how to read because it's gonna keep
her back from learning everything that
is based on knowing how to read in class
and knowing you know your numbers and
you have to move this entire cohort
together through the system so that the
teacher has an easier job teaching and
there was much more like the students
fed there's a plane and the amount of
emotional intelligence and interpersonal
intelligence they got was way ahead like
everyone I know who went to that school
knows how to talk to an adult knows how
to have their ideas heard knows how to
even in kindergarten like at least by
the end of kindergarten knows that they
can that they have a voice and I think
that is HUGE and so does anyone else
know of any solutions that are happening
in this space they get all touched on
our high school which was a regular
public high school in Alberta in the
nineties and still was pretty awesome
for what it was
there's a documentary made a couple of
years ago no more than a couple years
ago now anyway called Waiting for
Superman have any of you seen this film
no Bentley's nodding and that highlights
a I mean a it highlighted some of the
systemic blocks that there are to
actually you know a couple of
Commissioners whatever came along
actually tried to make changes actually
tried to make things better bring in new
models and the resistance they met from
the profession from the teaching unions
as well as from the administration you
know from the Department of Education
and so I was was insurmountable you know
so yeah there's there's that but the but
it also focused on a guy who started
schools I think I'm pretty sure they
were called Kipp schools Kay IP and
again I'm not sure what that stands for
but these are schools particularly
designed for deprived areas inner-city
kids because what sorry again I'm going
to go on for a minute here I do
apologize but studies and education
forever basically have always always
shown their children particularly black
children but children in general from
deprived areas never ever ever catch up
with their with their compadres in
higher demographics right they're
they're they're the outcomes the results
that they achieved never ever ever catch
up and it was thought that you know the
either the conditions in which they're
growing up or there's something about
the genes or whatever that is just not
possible these kids schools absolutely
turned that on their head by using this
model of you know fantastic teachers
really highly motivated doing it because
they love doing it that kind of thing
kids who are involved in the planning of
the curriculum and the organization at
the school and the disciplining of other
children it's really funny he made a
comment that you know after a couple of
years of the children deciding on what
the rules were they came up with exactly
the same rules that we had in the first
place right the point is they are they
own them they enforce them right they
are meaningful to if they understand the
point of them right and so you know
that's the models do exist at the Khan
Academy that that jubilee mentioned as
well you know models do exist they are
out there but there are massive barriers
to their implementation because of the
bureau
basic structures that exist that must be
able to compare one school with another
one student with another give this but
you know 15% of them get a is 20% of
them get B's every single year you know
what I mean this this whole apparatus
seems to me to be a huge barrier however
good your idea is you know however
perfect an educational system you design
actually getting it implemented is a
whole different kettle of fish right
sorry again I talk too long I apologize
yeah and if I can just add one point you
know we'll talk about the things that
kind of went wrong but there are there
are some like we might say rote learning
isn't something that we'd see in the
future but there are some types of
knowledge that rote learning is
important and can provide a lot of value
so I'm all for not yeah right because
once you learn that you can you can do
the other math so much quicker in your
head it makes it easier so yeah so
there's gonna be times for all these
different modalities of learning and but
yeah nothing should really be sacred in
our current plan we should be willing to
look at every piece and break it and
experiment where at the end of this this
section I also wanted to mention one of
the things our current education system
does for kids in particular is child
care that that is a big piece of that if
people are working and even if they're
not if they're just like have purpose a
place for kids to go and be kids
together is a one of the pieces that
education gives you that I think yes
socialization and the break for the
parents okay and then yes for both for
both parties right yeah and so now we
can go into the the amazing future that
however far the future you need that to
be for it to be possible Star Trek what
does education look like when we have
all the resources all the power people
came together and made an answer Bob
Laura's on the UN solution would anyone
like to start because I got ideas sure
is one of the really key parts that
anything to do with like educating a
populace has to take
to account is what people are interested
in like I've been interested in
technology and computers since I was a
kid and I worked with people who were
not that way whose parents put them in
technology they hated it and candidly
they weren't very good at it because it
didn't speak to them they didn't
practice in their spare time they didn't
you know go go to hackathons it was a
very telling thing and in tech that's
that's rampant there's people who love
it and who do it on the weekends and
evenings and it's their life there's
people who you can tell it's just a
paycheck and they'll easily leave it and
that's fine but the question is if they
weren't forced into tech what would they
have done and what they have been
world-class at it and I think that's a
huge part is having that be whatever
schooling ends up being you learn your
basics like you know you probably should
be able to read and write and and stuff
like that at some point in time but it's
somewhere in there there's that
divergence where you spend time figuring
out what it is you really like to do
ideally hopefully maybe some amount of
what do you already show some aptitude
for and then let that guide more
specific learning to do with what you
might actually end up doing this is also
part of sorry to jump in I plan not to
say anything in this because I've
already sought so much but this is part
of a wider thing right is that you know
if you want to do dance or you want to
do music or something like that if this
is your passion to actually be able to
earn a living from there at the other
end is extremely difficult and so what
you're talking about absolutely I agree
with all of it but it can't be done in
isolation of a change in the society
broadly as well where these things are
actually valued and rewarded and you can
you know you can you can live from doing
them kind of thing or live independently
of having to do anything right and that
might be down the line with like how
those courses end up so if you say oh
well I have an aptitude for dance or vo
or music or art part of the learning
might be okay just so you know at least
for right now those industries you know
you're rolling the dice as to whether or
not you're gonna be able to live
comfortably here's some strategies
here's some things Oh
maybe also find an alternate interest
because I have interests or examples
yeah yeah most I don't know of anyone
that has a single passion so maybe we
need change the words to say finding
your passions true I always speak about
a plural so yeah and then and then
yeah helping helping them and also
often passions are very are not like it
may not be danced it may be physical
movement and then maybe woodworking is
similar to dance if it unless you like
the being in front of other people and
then maybe if it's the self-expression
then it's that it's going into making
movies or something yeah but yeah a
guidance to make sure that if we're
still in a game a world that it could be
something that they could make a living
off of this interesting and while I have
the floor the future unless I forgot
what I was gonna say oh is that the
concept that learning is a lifelong
pursuit
so you made spend a higher priority of
your time during the formative years of
being a young person but maybe the
processes that we build would be
something that continued it'd be nice if
I had a way to track my learning these
are the skills I've learned and here's a
chart of that kind of like they do in
video games where you have skills and
they build on each other I've always
wanted that and there are some tools
that then you can use that throughout
your whole life I think speaking about
the future since you mentioned Star Trek
and stuff like that this sort of enters
in that vein I really think they're just
in the future there should be a digital
complex where we encourage diversity and
being able to have modules being able to
like if you want to dance but you also
want to do carpeting for example you
could just mix that into a degree and
literally in the digital complex there
will be this almost infinite or
innumerable library of videos that we
can have access to that will be saved
with that will be saved on a server and
the issue to me would be the issue of
making sure that everyone has an
individualized experience so I think the
future of Education would be a mixture
of finding a way to
um merge private tooter ship with the
digital complex of getting access to the
lectures that you want at a certain time
and then of course you have to add like
what you guys were talking about the
final little sweet spot which is you got
to make sure that you get employment
from that and you got to make sure that
it's it's it's accredited in some sense
it's not necessarily authoritarian but
you can actually look upon this library
and if you and people actually a firm
what you've done and it can actually get
a good analysis I think in the future
we're gonna have education that's
tailored to your interests for sure and
also to your learning style and helping
you figure out what those things are so
like Bentley said we're having a way to
be able to track your interest having a
way to be able to track your skills and
as they increase having a way to gamify
that if you want to and making it so
that it is it is very individually based
but at the same time as I'm able to
learn math people who is brains work
like mine would be able to learn from
what I've learned right so so it could
actually help you figure out what math
course would be the best for you if you
want to learn math so like following
your interests but also helping you
figure out what your learning style is
and having it be lifelong where it's not
about necessarily going and getting a
four-year degree but hey I want to take
this math course or it can offer if you
want to do this if you're gonna probably
need this stuff you don't to be able to
understand that and even if it's hard
we're gonna try to make it as easy as
possible within your learning style and
including virtual reality so that you
could have personal one-on-one tutors
without it necessarily being a one like
Nick doesn't need to teach Jubilee and
take his time to teach me it could be
like a virtual Nick teaching me right so
if you're an expert and never told me
teaching you and so also I don't think
that we need to teach kids for
employments in the future because I
think that employment with you be I and
with other resources it's not about
making a living it's about making a
purpose and so for some people that's
going to be very tailored it's going to
be you like
and everything's tack or you like
medicine and being a surgeon and
everything is that but for other people
it's gonna be so flowy I mean I watch
how my kid learns and it's like ballet
one week and minecraft the next and
being able to say yes follow your follow
your passion follow it you want to learn
and then teaming up with other people
that both have the skill sets you don't
have to be able to work on a team and
work towards a project from the age of
five and six like why not work on
projects why not have things that are
actually tangible like what happened
with the last last week some digital
native having the students add to the
learning curriculum right and having it
be like it's okay if there's millions of
videos on world war ii which ones are
the best for your brain which ones are
the best for you to understand which
ones do we agree are the truth and all
the reason making sense making reason
making technology that helps you have
access to data that is usable and
understandable at your fingertips so
that you don't need to memorize
everything and having it be and it will
be a little more silent because I just a
future oh just to add to that real quick
you can even think make things more
complicated as we're talking about the
future and I really don't think this is
too far-fetched but let's say I'm a
teacher I teach metaphysics and I have
someplace to go I can't necessarily be
there live or I can't necessarily
produce lectures within a specific kind
of way that can like let's say if you're
more of a visual learner perhaps I can't
do I can't perform in that manner
literally and this is maybe mm 150 years
in the future when we have a GI you will
be able to take the using neural
networks all the capacity of my sense
data and then make it into like what you
said like a virtual kind of thing and
then the virtual me will teach me and
it'll be a neural network it will be a
hologram that can literally mimic me so
perfectly that even it will teach me
some new things about learning
metaphysics so there will not be this
limitation of
out all we can only learn what the human
mind is capable of but there literally
be these huge undescribable branches
going on in all these different
directions and it would that would take
us forever to be able to like talk about
keenly today
I would like to said in the future we've
got past the notion of institutional
accreditation right I mean have no idea
how this would work it's just a kind of
picture in my head of this giant like
interface of everything with everything
kind of thing and so you know sort of
what you blue is talking about I want to
learn about this who is there out there
nearby me you know I want to learn how
to play the guitar right who is there
nearby me who knows how to play the
guitar and you know because we are no
longer having to go out and spend 50
hours a week to earn our crust in order
to keep our heads above water people
have time and there is nothing more
pleasurable if you're an expert at
something or even if you're proficient
at something to teach somebody and
professional about it to teach somebody
else about it is one of the greatest
joys that there is you know what I mean
so everybody becomes potentially a
teacher of things that they know about
and everybody is a learner of stuff that
they want to know about you know what I
mean in it and that that is the end that
starts you know what I mean it starts
that day Dalton finishes that there you
go in the ground
yes and so yeah so I think adding on to
all the virtual stuff that Nick was
talking to the digital stuff but also
the ability to both find peers that are
at the same learning stage you in your
physical space which I'm a big person
for digital stuff but there's a there's
a place for real people being in
physical proximity or video or you know
just all the different ways that we can
link together because sometimes the
other person you want to learn with is
on the other side of the planet but if
there is someone in your in your town or
within driving distance or
transportation distance then it would be
nice to have that as a possibility and
then as peers and then also as teachers
and as tutors I kind of have the feeling
that in the future and I really think
the biggest thing that teachers bring to
the situation is really more tutoring
than teaching just because you know
there's many many modalities for
learning something written video audio
that I don't know there might be a
modality toy you learn best from a human
being
being interactive like being able to ask
questions there's something that I
haven't heard that but I think I think
but that still I think would fall under
tutoring I'd you know that right now it
seems like we have thousands of teachers
creating their own curriculum or when
really they should be collected app ting
a curriculum to individual children and
I know a lot of them do that as well but
and I could definitely be wrong about
this but it just seemed like there was a
lot of spinning of wheels of teachers
kind of spending time creating
curriculum as opposed to adapting to
each individual child and of course not
being given the time to do that but yeah
if the if the individuals can adapt the
curriculum or pull it out then that
might be even better but there will
still be a place for for specific
teachers to help adapt curriculum to
different people and teach them how to
adapt it and then yeah and then not not
like a central accreditation I don't see
I don't see there being degrees because
that's kind of weird that's the whole
reason to have a degree is because it
was simpler for people to understand but
if we have systems in place then it
would just be like someone else said a
document of kind of what you've at least
attempted to learn what you've spent
time on and then I don't know if we'll
also want to have some sort of
measurement system that says how well
did you kind of learn this I don't know
if that's important but it'd be helpful
to have that knowledge graph of each
individual and then you could find when
you want to collaborate with people on a
project to find people that have the
skill sets that might help the project
which is another thing we're doing one
of the things I wanted to say about the
future is that teachers like when you
have UB I covered the people who are
teaching are doing people who want to
teach whether that's kids or adults it's
gonna be that that is part and we're all
gonna be teachers and students
constantly so maybe I don't consider
myself a teacher but I'm teaching you
the one thing that I'm adding to the
curriculum and also in the future having
maker spaces for things of all ages so
all interests and all like if you can go
and look under a microscope because you
want to and see what things look like be
able to have actual access to that
lifelong shops that you can create you
know
anything your your mind desires with the
help of other people who that's their
passion right helping people create
their their vision to to reality and the
more we're able to share in that right
sharing tools sharing space for various
ages and skill levels maybe those
microscopes that you don't get let's
stare at a certain skill level right and
and what Bentley said like knowing where
your skills are so you can be matched up
with other people and a project you have
the best people on it a great team of
people right who are taught but you can
always work on a project like this
conversation we're having were maybe all
a little bit expert at this but I think
you can get any five people together and
they could come up with eighth something
right and so it's it's like what what
level do you want to talk to people at
but it doesn't mean that everyone can
participate in it one more little tiny
aspirational thing to add that came to
my mind while Bentley was talking that
education in the future will be not
about as it largely is now not about so
that the world can judge you you know
what I mean of what do you know how well
have you learned this not it's not about
that it's about your own wish to find
out about things and discover things and
improve yourself right so it actually
turns the whole feeling of it if you
like on its head you know what I mean is
instead of being viewed by the world
because of what you've learned you have
learned what you've learned because you
want it to learn it it's a whole
different thing yeah I know Nick looks
like he's about to want to talk but I
think a drill hasn't shared in this
section and then it's time to go on to
the next section of like what's possible
now so building on families like
statement there I one of the interesting
things we're talking about sort of
specializing in your interests and in
your passions I think part of that too
is and this is something that game a is
terrible at is they've just sort of
great different skills for no apparent
reason
like deterrent marketer or something
like you need you know ten different
skills that almost no one has that
combination and whereas somebody might
be you know great at documentation or
explaining or whatever skill that is
that would also be useful somewhere else
and they're not good at you know
copywriting
but because they're in that role that's
just what they do I think teaching
suffers from the same challenge where
you have somebody who's good at like
trying to to relay information to trying
to you know sort of alternate how to
explain something but they might be not
very good at making curriculum and they
might also not be you know like a
world-class expert in that topic so that
you know 100 percent of what they're
showing is you know as reasonably as we
can be certain to be correct so I part
of it it is separating that you have
your library of knowledge you have you
know all your curriculum made by people
who are the best who you know and not
just the best as far as they know it the
best also they're the best at making
curriculum and making it so that you
could take something complex and explain
it in a way that can make sense to
somebody who's you know five or somebody
who's ten or somebody who's fifteen or
somebody who's at a different stage in
learning about that thing I want to say
as far as accreditation goes there needs
to be something to make sure that like
people note like I don't really care if
you know most accreditation goes away
but like if if I go to see a doctor I
want some assurance that they're you
know that they've got some base level of
knowledge if we put an engineer in
charge of building a bridge I want to
make sure you know hey that we can be as
reasonably confident as possible that
that's not going to collapse when you
know three cars were on at the same time
but I do agree that most accreditation
is kind of pointless and people just get
a degree to to take a box and then what
people who have master's degrees working
in a job that you don't need a master's
degree to do just because they wanted to
take a box and get that thing absolutely
so now we've we've talked about what's
wrong and right with the current one
what it could look like in the future
now we're gonna go into something that
is actually possible that is an
invitation not coercive enforce that ten
thousand people could get together and
create with a hundred thousand dollars
so again I have ideas but if anyone else
would like to like to start and will
this build on it so it doesn't
necessarily need to be something that is
like if next thing counteracts my thing
that's fine is it doable
is it within that budget and that number
of people
I really think what's doable now there's
this thing called the floating
University and it was this weird little
micro project that was occurring
somewhere I'm not quite sure the year
maybe 2012-2013 and it was twelve
lectures from 12 from 12 really
different topics from demography to
psychology to linguistics and the
theoretical physics and if we could tap
into that if we create if I think we can
create a medium between teachers
themselves and a library of videos in
order to be able to express themselves I
really think that that's possible now
with a certain form of networking an
investment in servers and just getting
people to really express what knowledge
that they have and be open when they're
talking in a lecture like for example
like we're talking about accreditation
and how it's kind of ridiculous in most
cases people should just say okay yeah
I'm gonna teach metaphysics but there
are some things of course that I don't
know about metaphysics and let's walk
through this together and then you
should feel like the lecture is
interactive and maybe we with with an
application that reaches out to teachers
and creating that and creating a bridge
into making videos I think that that's
really the easiest solution and we can
talk about how that would relate to
physical spaces and with places without
internet and the little complexities I
have we're talking about teachers there
was just this little thing that was like
a teacher spends so much of their time
doing the class planning right which I
don't think they know how to yet tailor
make it to the kid especially within the
current system but having that be
something that they could tap into a
reason or space and say you know this is
what I did last year and so I can just
redo my own but also sharing amongst
each other
so that they can say like here's my
lesson plan and sharing that with one
another so there's there's a database no
matter what you're teaching and then
those could also made available to
people anywhere in the world can be
translated right so so what happens in
in China to teach math translate it into
English is like oh wait that's all we do
this is really interesting and could be
a possibility something that could be
made now such things do exist at least
in the UK such things do already exist
quite extensively actually there's quite
a wide network of teachers who share and
use each other's lesson plans they
upload them to a website and other
people can use them if they want to kind
of think so it does already exist but I
do agree there's no international
a bigger burden is that internet I feel
might actually you know malcontent I
know if you go to tes Co UK there's a
section on there resources and that's
that's that's I mean thousands and
thousands of teachers upload lesson
plans and tests and all kinds of stuff
and as you quite rightly say there's no
point in 10,000 teachers essentially
doing exactly the same work right one
person can do it well and everyone else
can share it you know me and then tweak
it as they want to for their own
particular purposes you know so yeah you
know I absolutely agree with that it's a
shocking ridiculous waste of time the
lack of coordination of that kind of
thing especially given how standardized
the curricular again I speak for the UK
you know but basically every single
school teaches essentially exactly the
same content you know what I mean and
they do exactly the same exams and they
are exactly the same basic mechanism of
going from plastic plastic plastic
plastic glass I mean III really I really
like your idea in it the ideas you've
expressed generally throughout this of a
sort of blend between a digital library
and and actual teaching in order me and
I also think the notion that Bentley
mentioned of the tutor role you know the
guidance thing not the delivering of
content but the guidance thing I think
is I think is also a really important
idea that the idea occurred to me of a
sort of meta learning that needs to take
place really quite early in life you
know where you
you learn about your learning if you see
what I mean and so you understand what
works for you and that would allow you
to self tutor to a certain degree I'm
not saying you wouldn't need some
guidance from the outside as well but
you could do a great deal of self
tutoring in that respect if you had a
nice wide open field that you can go but
but but all of this stuff all of this
stuff and this is really my point in
this section and I'd pretty sure jubilee
knows what's coming but all of this is
you know none of these innovations are
possible while the needs to evaluate
outcomes in this current way that we
have right we're you know this is your
grade point average of this many people
get a's and this many people get B's and
this many people go to this great
university most mediocre universities go
to universities and so on this
whole this whole treadmill thing in my
opinion revolves around one thing which
is the notion of standardized testing
you know in the UK as GCSEs and a-levels
at the ages of 16 and 18 respectively in
the u.s. is the SATs in the UK as well
even ages 7 and 11 kids sit these
standards are you offering the
standardized testing topic just because
we're talking about what is possible and
so we can't we can't change standardized
testing right now 10,000 people at
$100,000 actually probably flip it
around okay so so MD and standardized
testing would be one of the things that
we could that is a very little money
zero downside zero risk because if you
don't reach the threshold number then
nothing happens right and so nobody uses
anything all the people at our
maintenance yeah and because there's
also like even if schools are doing
standardized testing having a learning
system outside but if it was engaging
enough kids would want to spend an hour
two four hours on it a week learning
with their peers or and to me that is
something that you can do that isn't
requiring me sorry in addition to their
six hours of mandatory schooling yeah I
mean if it's engaging and they do soccer
they do ballet they DS piano they do
you don't I mean like what do you want
to learn here are other people who want
to learn that and then facilitating
finding a course or creating a course
and adults can do that as well right
it's saying hey I want to learn many
stories they say but what about all the
parents that you know you should be
spending all that extra time gaining
extra credit because you won't get into
the top university if you don't get
extra credit blah blah blah blah blah
you know this isn't about convincing
that's why it's only ten thousand people
right it's ten thousand parents or ten
thousand kids so it's about how could I
get my kid something she's interested in
without requiring I don't need her to
get into university I don't need I want
her to be happy I want her to be engaged
I'm you know so what resources could I
create with other parents that are like
me so that I could give that to my kid
and then I think other people would see
what that gives to your kid and they
would want to be part of it but that's
not that's not a guarantee that's just
hopefully what happens it's as
Invitational right it's something that
does give you something right away it
gives the kid enjoyment and learning if
it's a feedback system or like wait
they're not choosing to be on this I
have to force them to be on it okay well
that's not working what would make it
more fun what would make it more
engaging oh just to add to what you guys
are saying and this could this goes into
resources as well and I really think
there's a simple way to achieve these
types of things within education
everything that we've mentioned in
discriminatory form of psychoanalysis
that's individualistic the main problem
is that people not not teachers mostly
but institutions lack the basic decency
and don't understand the deep
complexities of a person's psyche to be
able to even consider that as as a
category for making making a curriculum
so well if I just say something like oh
you know just tailor it to someone
psychology the the typical reaction is
like are you nuts how we're gonna do
that I said well that's a good question
you could do that with with $10,000 oh
sorry what was it a hundred thousand
yeah see you could do that because all
you have to do is spark that attitude
because we are we think it's impossible
and that's why we continue to use
statistics as a basis for measuring
people and measuring how things are
going and having all the grades but in
fact we're using statistics on something
that is very ambiguous when it comes to
measurement and that is the human mind
and I think it's absurd that we exist in
this level of reality where it's like
maybe if we just find this one equation
to kind of simplify how people act in
groups maybe we could develop a
curriculum it doesn't work that way and
that's why I emphasize on the digital
space because I really think there needs
to be a form of preservation and a form
of possibility and infinitely
personalizing to the kids unto the
people who are trying to learn and you
have to start with the digital first
because if you don't have that
preservation space and you don't have
the potential to infinitely personalize
to the person's leisure to actually help
them then you cannot create a physical
space that will appeal in every single
thing the person needs psychologically
and that's my opinion so let me throw an
idea out there and it's kind of building
on some things that people have been
working on and like Khan Academy so
creating an online resource that builds
a custom curriculum for each individual
based on like there's there's no honor
and and in the United States we have the
option of doing homeschooling so the way
of kind of getting them out of the six
to eight hour grind of school is you
know you designate your kids as
homeschooling we make it as easy as
possible for the parents to do that and
they have resources to find other
students in the area and other tours in
the area and the kind of system that
tracks what you've attempted to learn
there might have to be a tool
temporarily that's that matches it up
against the standardized testing and the
expectations of the area that you're in
to help make sure that in a way too
what's your current interests and bring
that in so if you're learning dance if
you if you like dancing maybe learning
about the mathematics of movement and
stuff could help you learn enough about
the math it's kind of a thing we'd want
anyways and then kind of track your
knowledge skill and help encourage you
to learn the things necessary to pass
the standardized tests and then have it
also include within it some that record
so that maybe we can get beyond the
whole idea of having go to an Ivy League
college because there's a lot of
evidence that there's not an actual
value in the in the actual education
there's a value in having that name on
your resume but it's not worth the the
cost right now so I think it wouldn't
solve any of those issues solidly but it
would kinda it sounds like it might be
good to have kind of a platform like
that that would then allow us to
experiment with Nick's ideas about sake
you know using some psychology to to
focus it on what would be best for the
student and Eric's concerns about the
about the standardized tests and create
an alternative and show it working or I
have a area to experiment with stuff
like that that then later we can use to
convince others of these better
solutions yeah I don't know how it is in
the UK or in the United States but I
know here in Canada you are allowed to
'unschool your kid you are allowed to
not take them out of standardized
testing including in school but then of
course they can't get into University
and they can't do those things but also
just to say that like my kid doesn't
need this my kid can follow their
passion and do and that's hard to do
within a system where everyone else is
ranked and it comes with a disadvantage
but when there's enough people who are
learning in that way and able to come
together and find their peers and like
it starts to be omni wind from day one
like i already can see that after two
years of school in the democratic
community what that does for children
and then and the teenagers that come out
of that and like they're ready to be in
this world in a way that other high
schoolers aren't
so although they don't have the
credentials to necessarily get into
university and a lot of them do they
have the the skill set to be a lifelong
learner and to critique things and to
have their voice heard which is better
in some ways than having in a lot of
ways than having the credentials yeah
yeah just just to add to that and and
this is a problem with almost every
field of study and and I've noticed this
in game B as well where the
hyper-rational people like to think that
we already figured out the secret to how
to be a person now we can work on all
the problems of like how do we how do we
communicate how do we do this but in
fact we have not found the secret to how
to be a person our own person yet so
education should have that same thing
it's like hey I'm still figuring myself
out I'm a work in progress I know some
things and other things I don't but if
you look at any field of study including
education there is still this myth that
it's like well clearly you're alive and
you're a person and you can think for
yourself that's enough and it would be
enough if education didn't have a
specific definition of what a person is
we're all unique we're all our own you
individuals and immediately when we try
to put personhood as a defined quality
that's where things break down and
that's why like how you're mentioned you
believe when when we get people in that
kind of environment and when we unschool
them and we teach them social skills and
we just get them in the raw realm of
experience and that's where things begin
to learn that's where wonder and
curiosity and emotion and thought all
grow from in order to achieve this
higher education of like oh yes I want
to think philosophically I want to think
about why I'm here you have to have a
stable you have to have a stability in
yourself where you feel like you know
I'm enough of a person that I feel like
I can I can abstract for myself but most
of us if not all of us can and do that
yet and we shouldn't feel peer pressured
to feel like we already have that luck
I just realized a pretty big hole in my
suggestion that a lot of people don't
have the luxury to home-school because
it still takes a lot of attention or
someone to watch so you'd still need
some sort of either either do an actual
school or have a resource to where
parents can group together and create a
space that their children can go during
the day while they're head doing their
game a jobs that they could then
participate in a situation like this so
maybe also facilitating those that kind
of school replacement for those that
need it general point but the notion of
experimentation space to experiment
several of you have said that in one
context to another and I wonder whether
a good first step might not be thinking
about how to create those spaces to
actually experiment without it impacting
too much other people do the experiment
you know then that that that freedom to
experiment with stuff feels like a
really good starting point yeah I think
like building on what we've talked about
and with like specific goal of you know
the ten thousand people and a hundred
thousand dollars and talking about
having some sort of like an online you
know repository or or or marketplace for
curriculum I think if you like step one
explicitly try to identify the different
learning styles and specifically where
existing education falls flat and focus
on the areas where typical education
doesn't really handle it that well and
offer that as a tool to existing people
and say oh if your kid isn't doing well
in math in standardized testing that
might be because they don't have this
one learning style the education focuses
on here's another three and then you can
start to help kids a get better at
Saturday's to testing with education
gear towards their learning style and
then also you don't care about that and
you just want to learn it same thing
same content there's yeah you're still
learning it it's just do you have to
learn it because you're trying to fit
into standardized testing and you want
to get into school and et cetera
still helps there or no it's not a part
of that my kid just shows like you know
they want to be an engineer so they need
to understand these topics great you can
go do that even if your school's not
testing for it a lot yeah that sounds
like a really good kind of path for
creating this is start with augmenting
the current education system with all
the tools we've discussed and then
slowly dominate replace exactly and then
if it gets big enough you might actually
end up where oh we actually made a deal
with some you know schools or some
education where now you can get credits
for it you get you you actually
completed these sets of curriculum you
can absolutely do do that like there are
if you make a deal with certain
organizations it's now like yep that
counts as a credit all these schools
will accept it go ahead
yeah and build it out to where the
schools can also use any of the tools
that we have and encourage that so that
they can if they choose they can start
implementing this process internally
right and then you end up with a like a
full collection and this might even sort
of be related to last week's topic of
the digital native system where you have
old students of that like who actually
learned it but we're like you know what
I didn't like how the existing
curriculum taught it like I did terrible
in school because I didn't teach like I
don't learn how schools teach and so I
struggled through a lot of it and if I
could then go back especially if there
was some sort of a framework of here's
the different ways people learn here's
the areas we have this part covered
already is the education system if you
learned it this way you know by hearing
information and then you can write a
test if that's how you learn you're
already set we can have some stuff
working but really you're probably off
to the race anyway everyone else here's
the gaps that we're trying to fill sorry
you know if we don't have these ones yet
well we'll just try to get them but if
you have these two learning styles we
can help you now oh now we just added
the third one and the fourth one I start
to build that content and then start to
rank of yeah that helps my learning
style but it's not a great content oh
that one is and I think a lot of it is
is possibly curating what's already out
there and TED Talks and YouTube videos
in like having a debate for it's like
here's what I
learn or eat door if it's for kids
here's what my kid wants to learn and
then how you like you said if you're
interested is interests or ballet and
nine craft there's a lot you can learn
with us like here's how they would might
learn math and here's here is someone
teaching that or and then it can also
showcase what doesn't exist right like
there are no ballerina math YouTube
videos strangely so but then people
would know to create that right
guaranteed there's people who are into
ballet and math who could make it and
then possibly putting them together with
someone who knows how to actually make a
youtube video so it sounds a bit like
you want the same cut sort of catalog
that that we've all mentioned I think
it's some form or another
you you track what it's trying to teach
you possibly like auxilary things of
late methods to use right like hey if
your kid likes minecraft here's all
these things on how you can teach
different topics using minecraft but
then a specific here's what this
curriculum here's the learning style
that it is you know trying to help or
it's trying to appease or fulfill that
need
and then yeah if you have a essentially
a database of curriculums
with these you know topics and learning
styles you can then say show me the gaps
oh look hey it's no you know or there's
one piece of curriculum for you know
trying to teach math to somebody with
this look learning style let's go great
that I don't know this is impossible at
all with a hundred thousand dollars and
ten thousand people but having like my
kids on YouTube and she chooses what she
watches and there's of course the
YouTube algorithm that tells her the
next one to watch but if it could learn
that and actually be like oh you like
Minecraft and LPS here's math right like
one that comes up and like add it on to
YouTube where it's like hey this is
actually gonna teach them to use they
like social media like try to get your
time but like use it to help people like
did I just learn relative physics what's
going on that's so funny
because I am literally working on a
neural network that already has that
specific function the neural network is
not created for that function but could
very easily go
in that direction because I'm trying to
because I'm very interested in the
essence of thought not necessarily
computation or complexity but the actual
quality the substance of thought
whatever it's made out of and how it
operates metaphysically and I'm trying
to get the neural network to kind of
move in that direction of like okay if
this if this is implemented on to me
well it could lead here and then oh look
at that that could lead to that and that
could lead to all these other branches
and so that's literally what the neural
network does now and it didn't cost me
any money you just you just look up free
neural network programs and and like
most of this doesn't require any money
it just requires a lot of people willing
to take the time to put in the research
and then organize and actually be
activists in that domain but the
difficulty is getting our psychological
states in tune what we intellectually
want to accomplish and then being able
to network in a decent way to be able to
convince people that hey I'm authentic
enough you can trust me we just really
got a stick with it I really think that
those are the two key issues that we
have yet to accomplish yet I just wanted
to ask we've come with a lot of ideas
during this this half an hour there are
a lot of them very feasible with the ten
thousand and hundred thousand dollars
is there anyone like literally any of
those things I would throw $10 at like
if that could exist in six months to a
year for me in humanity I would
absolutely put money towards that am I
the only one like would you need that to
be exactly what you wanted it to be like
all the features you want it to be and
under features you didn't in order to
put $10 towards it or would like
literally any step in the right
direction I would throw $10 towards
nobody like that if it seemed like it
would go there and to be fair a lot of
what we talked about the technical part
is fairly easy a lot of it is based on
like being able to categorize and like
really dissect education and learn
like most of my assumption was based on
the fact that we've identified and you
know we know what the learning styles
are if they're still a bunch of work
they're to be done we can't do that with
a hundred thousand dollars if that
information already exists we're just
saying oh here's this you know five
seven ten learning sales however many
there are we can just plug that into a
system then it's actually fairly easy
and then it's just trying to get the
content and possibly find existing
content and categorize it yeah and I and
I think to jubblies idea just link to
the existing content as much as possible
resource to to store it also it for if
it doesn't exist anywhere yeah I would
put ten dollars a month
towards that with just those goals and
then you know if I see it completely
going off the rails that not stop
funding but I'd definitely be willing to
put some money into a patreon and but
and I think to get that started you
would need like a one pager and then
ideally it'd be good to have some people
that have done some work in this space
be the people trusted to over look the
projects so that I think those are the
two things you need to need a team and
you need a description a one-page
description yeah we're not actually
gonna do that but you guys like to come
and then after doing several of these
showcasing that like 10,000 people with
$10 each can change any industry how do
we get 10,000 people right how do we
actually bring people together to have
this conversation and then pick one and
then like work through that process but
right now it's just what is the
possibility what is the thing we could
create and we came up with a bun should
it be like organizing what would we need
right what would we need to do what are
the features and benefits and then what
would we need for each feature in
benefit right learning styles well there
needs to be learning styles we need to
know what they are do they exist in
order to be able to do that and working
through that process which can't be done
in an hour but is absolutely possible
all of these things are feasible and the
kind of thing especially done out in the
open with everyone being able to be
involved are amazing
I agree I think this was a good first
solution reason I tried it all right to
say goodbye you can say goodbye to
YouTube unless anyone else has any
closing thoughts they would like to say
on me
all right goodbye YouTube